Manling YANG

Research interests

I have keen interest in empirical study in data visualization and humancomputer interaction, working with researchers from different fields or interacting with users of different backgrounds makes me feel passionate. Specifically, my research interests include:

- Cognition and perception, how different visual designs affect user behavior.
- Discovery methods to help designers improve creativity and productivity.

Education

The Hongkong University of Science And Technology (Guangzhou)

MPhil student of Computational Media and Arts Sep. 2023 – Present Mentors: Prof. Wei Zeng, Prof. Luwen Yu

Chongqing University

B.Eng. in Electronic Information Engineering Sep. 2019 – Jun. 2023 Mentors: Prof. Jinglan Ou, Prof. Li Liu

Honors and scholarships

Comprehensive Scholarship (2nd Class), Chongqing University	9/2022
Comprehensive Scholarship (3rd Class), Chongqing University	3/2023
Exchange Program Scholarship, Chongqing University	8/2021

Publications

Dashboard Vision: Using Eye-Tracking to Understand and Predict Dashboard Viewing Behaviors

Manling Yang, Yihan Hou, Ling Li, Remco Chang, and Wei Zeng. *in submission*

FinFlier: Automating Graphical Overlays for Financial Visualizations with Knowledge-Grounding Large Language Model

Jianing Hao, **Manling Yang**, Qing Shi, Yuzhe Jiang, Guang Zhang, Wei Zeng. in submission

C2Ideas: Supporting Creative Interior Color Design Ideation with Large Language Model

Yihan Hou, **Manling Yang**, Hao Cui, Lei Wang, Jie Xu, and Wei Zeng . *Proceedings of The ACM CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems*, 2024. Accepted.

A Survey of Computer Vision-Based Fall Detection and Technology Perspectives

Manling Yang, Xiaohu Li, Jiawei Liu, Shu Wang, and Li Liu. *CCF Conference on Computer Supported Cooperative Work and Social Computing (ChineseCSCW 2022)*.

Research experience

IOT & MOTION BIGDATA LAB

Mentors: Prof. Li Liu (Chongqing University)

Apr. 2022 – Jun. 2023

Research focuses on how to use computer vision and other related techniques combined with causal learning to improve elderly fall detection.

Image-based Cable Cross-sectional Parameter Measurement System

Mentors: Prof. Yangfan Huang (Chongqing University) May. 2021 – May. 2022

Research training project, with students in the same major to develop a portable vision-based automated cable quality inspection.

Teaching experience

Teaching assistant, Digital Electronic Technology

Fall 2022

School of Microelectronics and Communication Engineering, Chongqing Uni-

versity

Main work: exercise class lectures, homework corrections, etc.

Average student rating: 4.71/5.

Work

Research Assitant in CIVAL Lab

Jun. 2023 – Aug. 2023

experience The Hongkong University of Science And Technology (Guangzhou)

Assisted with CHI2024's submission, including data collection and statistics,

execution and analysis of user study, etc.

Skills

Programming

Programming: Python, MATLAB, Latex.

Software: Figma, Illustrator.

Computing: PyTorch, Tensorflow, Sklearn, Numpy, Pandas, etc.

Service

Student Volunteer, VINCI 2023

Sep. 2023.